jantakareporter.com 2018-12-27

# Privacy Policy - Janta Ka Reporter

Last Updated: 20th May 2018

## Privacy Policy of Janta Ka Reporter

Your privacy is of utmost importance to us here at Janta Ka Reporter. Rest assured that any information you provide will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement. We only share your information with the trusted companies and our advertisers.

This policy may be updated or changed anytime and we encourage you to review it whenever you visit the site to make sure you understand how any personal information you provide will be used. This policy was last updated in May 2018 after the initial draft on May 2015.

> 
>     Email for contact: jkrcontact@gmail.com

**Twitter**

**Retweets don’t mean  endorsements: **Retweet doesn’t mean any endorsement. Janta Ka Reporter official twitter account can retweet on the following terms

  * Its interesting tweet for viewers
  * Some interesting fact relating to our country
  * Endorsement by anyone
  * The tweet has mentioned @JantaKaReporter or/and used jantakareporter.com url in between. It’s strictly not a type of endorsement. We may not agree with the comment written.

#### **Collection and Use of Information**

We may collect personally identifiable information such as names and email addresses only when voluntarily submitted. This information are used merely to fulfill a specific request, for example, to post a comment on our blog, to create an account in our Forum, or to subscribe to our mailing list. All emails and newsletters from this site allow you to opt out of further communications.

#### **Distribution of Information**

We never use or share any of that information in ways unrelated to the ones described above. We do not send spam and we do not sell your information to any company for marketing purposes. We may, however, share information with government agencies or other companies assisting us in fraud prevention or investigation. We may do so when: (1) permitted or required by law; (2) trying to protect against or prevent actual or potential fraud or unauthorized transactions; or (3) investigating fraud which has already taken place.

#### **Cookies and Tracking Technology**

Our site may place a small file, called a cookie, on your hard drive to provide you with a better website. A cookie does not, in any way, give us access to your computer or to any personally identifiable information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us. It only helps us analyze web traffic or lets web applications respond to you as an individual.

Our authorized third-party advertisers in the course of serving ads to you, may also place cookies on your browser or use tracking technology to collect information. You can choose not to accept cookies by modifying your browser settings. At any time, you may remove any cookie stored on your hard drive by deleting them in your browser’s settings section.

Google, one of our third-party advertisers, may add a cookie to determine targeted advertisements based on your preferences and your visit to our site and other sites on the internet. You can choose to opt out of Google’s use of cookies by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy.

We believe in open communication if you have any query regarding Janta Ka Reporter.

Please email us on jkrcontact@gmail.com

#### **Links to other Websites**

Our site may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you use these links to leave our site, we do not anymore have control over that website. Such sites are not governed by this privacy statement and we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information you provide to those sites. Exercise caution and read the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

### Who we are

Our website address is http://www.jantakareporter.com owned by Rifster Media Pvt. Ltd.

### What personal data we collect and why we collect it

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Media

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

### Contact forms

If you fill contact form on our website to reach out, your data such as email, IP and Phone Number will remain with us for next 3 months.

### Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to save your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### Analytics

### Who we share your data with

  * Google Analytics
  * Google AdSense
  * Google Services
  * Twitter
  * Facebook
  * Yum India Pvt Ltd (Analytical Data only)

### How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

### What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

We will respond to any queries or request for removal of private data within 100 hours.

### Where we send your data

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

### Additional information

#### How we protect your data

We respect your privacy and protect the data by providing only meaningful data to partners.

#### What automated decision making and/or profiling we do with user data

We flush the IP Address and other critical information saved in our database every 2 months.
